Guide to the Aubrey Wisberg Papers c.1945-1970 MSS 48 MSS.048
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series I: Film and television production typescripts
  - Patrol Boat 999, "Night Run From Nassau" (pilot script) written by Aubrey Wisberg, second draft, 10/27/1960, 0031142040610068 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Patrol Boat 999, "Deep Water" original teleplay by Aubrey Wisberg, number one., undated; 0031142040610068 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Patrol Boat 999, "Deep Water" television series created and written by Aubrey Wisberg, number one, undated; 0031142040610068 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Patrol Boat 999, "Hunter in the Night" teleplay by Aubrey Wisberg, number two, undated; 0031142040610068 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Patrol Boat 999, "Hunter in the Night" teleplay by Aubrey Wisberg, number two, missing epilogue, with book summary and review excerpts, undated; 0031142040610068 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Patrol Boat 999, "Shadow at Noon" teleplay by Aubrey Wisberg, with photograph, summary, and review excerpts of book, undated; 0031142040610068 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Patrol Boat 999, "Shadow at Noon" teleplay by Aubrey Wisberg, number three, undated; 0031142040610068 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Patrol Boat 999, "Shadow at Noon" teleplay by Aubrey Wisberg, number three, annotated., undated; 0031142040610068 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Patrol Boat 999, "Shadow at Noon" teleplay by Aubrey Wisberg, undated; 0031142040610068 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Patrol Boat 999, "Contraband!" original teleplay by Aubrey Wisberg, number four, undated; 0031142040610068 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Patrol Boat 999, by Harold Waters and Aubrey Wisberg. Published by the Chilton Company and Ambassador Books, undated; 0031142040610068 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - A Quiet Place by the Sea, a play in three acts by Aubrey Wisberg, undated; 0031142040610068 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - A Quiet Place by the Sea, a play in three acts by Aubrey Wisberg, undated; 0031142040610076 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - The Race Against Time, created and written by Aubrey Wisberg, treatment, episode 2, undated; 0031142040610076 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Return to Treasure Island, original screenplay by Aubrey Wisberg and Jack Pollexfen, undated; 0031142040610076 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Return to Treasure Island photographs of Aubrey Wisberg, Barbara Wisberg and Tab Hunter on location at Palos Verdes, Southern California, undated; 0031142040610076 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Revolt of the Robots, original screenplay by Aubrey Wisberg, missing many pages, undated; 0031142040610076 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Revolt of the Robots, original screenplay by Aubrey Wisberg, undated; 0031142040610076 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Revolt of the Robots, original screenplay by Aubrey Wisberg. Inserted newspaper article "The Domestic Robot: Ultimate in Home Appliances", undated; 0031142040610076 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Ride the Wild Wind, original screenplay by Aubrey Wisberg, undated; 0031142040610076 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Sand In My Shoes, by Aubrey Wisberg and Harold Waters, undated; 0031142040610076 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Sand In My Shoes, by Aubrey Wisberg and Harold Waters, undated; 0031142040610076 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Sand In My Shoes, coast guard photographs, undated; 0031142040610076 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Sand In My Shoes, by Aubrey Wisberg and Harold Waters, first chapter, undated; 0031142040610076 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - The Sand Pounder, by Harold Waters and Aubrey Wisberg [Alternate title to Sand In My Shoes], undated; 0031142040610076 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Satan's Daughters, original screenplay by Aubrey Wisberg, undated; 0031142040610076 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Scream on a Crooked Street, original screenplay by Aubrey Wisberg, undated; 0031142040610076 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Scream on a Dark Street, original screenplay by Aubrey Wisberg, undated; 0031142040610076 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - The Secret Gun, television series created and written by Aubrey Wisberg, episode number one: "Backtrack", undated; 0031142040610076 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - The Secret Gun, television series created and written by Aubrey Wisberg, episode number two: "The Race Against Time," with writing, undated; 0031142040610076 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - The Secret of Monste Island, [sic] original screenplay by Aubrey Wisberg [original title Island Adventure], undated; 0031142040610076 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - The Secret of Monster Island, original screenplay by Aubrey Wisberg, undated; 0031142040610076 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Second Floor Front, a play in three acts by Aubrey Wisberg, undated; 0031142040610076 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Second Floor Front Reviews of Texas performances in Daily News, undated; 0031142040610076 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Serpent in the Sun (synopsis), undated; 0031142040610076 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Serpent in the Sun, original screenplay by Aubrey Wisberg, undated; 0031142040610076 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Serpent in the Sun, original screenplay by Aubrey Wisberg, with extra, loose pages, undated; 0031142040610084 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Shadow of a Woman, original screenplay by Aubrey Wisberg, undated; 0031142040610084 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Shriek on a Crooked Street, original screenplay by Aubrey Wisberg, undated; 0031142040610084 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Shriek on a Crooked Street, original screenplay by Aubrey Wisberg, undated; 0031142040610084 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Shriek on a Dark Street, original screenplay by Aubrey Wisberg, undated; 0031142040610084 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Silver Platter, by Aubrey Wisberg, undated; 0031142040610084 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - The Sin of Sean O'Shaughnessy, by Aubrey Wisberg, manuscript and publication., undated; 0031142040610084 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Sinbad, Ali Baba and Aladdin, miscellaneous loose pages, undated; 0031142040610084 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Sinbad, Ali Baba and Aladdin, original screenplay by Aubrey Wisberg Song: "Mirage" lyrics by Aubrey Wisberg, undated; 0031142040610084 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Sinbad, Ali Baba and Aladin, [sic] original screenplay by Aubrey Wisberg Song: "Mirage" lyrics by Aubrey Wisberg, undated; 0031142040610084 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Souix City, [sic] by Eugene Ling and Aubrey Wisberg, April 15, 1943, 0031142040610084 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - The Slave Raiders, original screenplay by Aubrey Wisberg, original title indicated: The Sword and the Passion, undated; 0031142040610084 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - The Slave Raiders, original screenplay by Aubrey Wisberg, undated; 0031142040610084 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - The Slave Raiders, original screenplay by Aubrey Wisberg, undated; 0031142040610084 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Slave to a Far Planet, original screenplay by Aubrey Wisberg, undated; 0031142040610084 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Stranger in the Saddle, original screenplay by Aubrey Wisberg, original title indicated The Left Handed Gun, undated; 0031142040610084 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Stranger in the Saddle, original screenplay by Aubrey Wisberg, undated; 0031142040610084 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Success Story, by Aubrey Wisberg, revised version of Silver Platter, undated; 0031142040610084 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Sunday on the River, by Aubrey Wisberg, undated; 0031142040610084 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Tales from the Arabian Nights, original teleplay by Aubrey Wisberg, number one, undated; 0031142040610084 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Tales from the New Arabian Nights, original teleplay "conceieved and written by Aubrey Wisberg" [sic], number one, undated; 0031142040610084 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Target Minus Forty, original screenplay by Aubrey W, undated; 0031142040610084 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - A Taste of Paradise formerly known as Serpent in the Sun, original screenplay by Aubrey Wisberg, undated; 0031142040610084 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Theater of the Damned The Mad Dog, adapted by Aubrey Wisberg from the play by Alfred Savior and Leopold Marchand. Originally produced at the Belasco Theatre, Los Angeles California, undated; 0031142040610084 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Tillie Went to Tokyo by Aubrey Wisberg and Jack Pollexfen, undated; 0031142040610084 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - The Treasure of Tom Smith's Reef, original screenplay by Aubrey Wisberg, undated; 0031142040610084 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - The Trouble in Town, original screenplay by Aubrey Wisberg, undated; 0031142040610092 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - A Turn at Cards, no author listed, undated; 0031142040610092 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - A Turn at Cards, a play in one act by Aubrey Wisberg, undated; 0031142040610092 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - The Three Arabian Knights (A New Musical Play), libretto by Aubrey Wisberg, lyrics by Johnny Mercer, music by Franz Steininger, undated; 0031142040610092 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - The Three Arabian Knights, lyrics by Johnny Mercer, undated; 0031142040610092 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Up the Creek, by Aubrey Wisberg, undated; 0031142040610092 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - The Viking Raiders, original screenplay by Aubrey Wisberg, undated; 0031142040610092 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - The Viking Raiders, original screenplay by Aubrey Wisberg, undated; 0031142040610092 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - The Violent Drums, original screenplay by Aubrey Wisberg, with handwritten stage directions, undated; 0031142040610092 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - The Violent Drums, original screenplay by Aubrey Wisberg, undated; 0031142040610092 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - What Will the Neighbors Say! original screenplay by Aubrey Wisberg, with notes, undated; 0031142040610092 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - What Will the Neighbors Say! original screenplay by Aubrey Wisberg, undated; 0031142040610092 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - What Will the Neighbors Say? (A New Musical Play) book by Aubrey Wisberg Original title Piece de Resistance, undated; 0031142040610092 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - What Will the Neighbors Say! A musical play, book by Aubrey Wisberg, undated; 0031142040610092 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - What Will the Neighbors Say! original screenplay by Aubrey Wisberg, undated; 0031142040610092 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - What Will the Neighbors Say! A musical play, book by Aubrey Wisberg, undated; 0031142040610092 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - What Will the Neighbors Say! A musical play, book by Aubrey Wisberg, with notes, undated; 0031142040610092 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - What Will the Neighbors Say! A musical play, book by Aubrey Wisberg, with notes, undated; 0031142040610092 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - When the World Was Young, television series by Aubrey Wisberg, undated; 0031142040610092 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Young Jim Hawkins of Treasure Island, original screenplay by Aubrey Wisberg, undated; 0031142040610092 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Young Jim Hawkins of Treasure Island, television script by Aubrey Wisberg, number one, undated; 0031142040610092 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Young Jim Hawkins of Treasure Island, conceived and written by Aubrey Wisberg, with synopsis, undated; 0031142040610092 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Young Jim Hawkins of Treasure Island, television script by Aubrey Wisberg, number two "The Wreckers," writing, undated; 0031142040610092 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Young Jim Hawkins of Treasure Island, television script by Aubrey Wisberg, number two "The Wreckers," writing, undated; 0031142040610092 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Young Jim Hawkins of Treasure Island, television script by Aubrey Wisberg, number two "The Wreckers", undated; 0031142040610092 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Young Jim Hawkins of Treasure Island, original story and teleplay by Aubrey Wisberg, number three "The Smugglers," writing, undated; 0031142040610092 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Young Jim Hawkins of Treasure Island, original story and teleplay by Aubrey Wisberg, number three "The Smugglers," writing, undated; 0031142040610092 (Box 9, Folder 27)
- Series II: Miscellaneous materials
  Series II contains two boxes of miscellaneous and oversize collection materials.
  - The Amateur Sinner, 9 Songs, Audiocassette, undated; 0031142040610100 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - The Amateur Sinner, 9 songs, Audiocassette Music/Webb Lyrics/Matthews Concertape, 90 minutes, undated; 0031142040610100 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - The Amateur Sinner, 9 Songs, Audiocassette Sampling numbers Webb: Music, Matthews: Lyrics Concertape, 90 minutes, undated; 0031142040610100 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - 3 Arabian Knights, Audiocassette Johnny Mercer- Franz Steininger. Sung by M--- Nixon [first name illegible]. Scotch C-60, highlander/low noise cassette, undated; 0031142040610100 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Three Arabian Knights, one-fourth audiotape Commander Publications: Mercer Music 1209 North Western Avenue Hollywood, California 90029, undated; 0031142040610100 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - The Three Arabian Knights, one-fourth audiotape, demonstration tape seven and a half speed: ATandT 717 N. Highland Ave., Hollywood, Calif. 90038, undated; 0031142040610100 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - The Closed Book, by Aubrey Wisberg, undated; 0031142040610100 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - The Closed Book, by Aubrey Wisberg, missing pages, very worn, undated; 0031142040610100 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Envelope labeled "Second Floor Front, Media Reviews and Coverage," copies inside, undated; 0031142040610100 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Passion of Roger Corsair, original screenplay by Aubrey Wisberg. Original story by Aubrey Wisberg and Harry Hervey [Hervey's name is crossed out]. Previous title: Flash of Steel, undated; 0031142040610100 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous script parts, undated; 0031142040610100 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Unidentified short story, missing title and first pages, undated; 0031142040610100 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Published short stories, by Aubrey Wisberg: "Dark Charter," "Go on to Sea," "A Very Small Mutiny", undated; 0031142040610100 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Miscellaneous printed materials Our Navy, November, 1966, Our Navy, December 1965, Skipper: the magazine for yachtsmen, August 1964, 1964-1966; 0031142040610100 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, undated; 0031142040610100 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Miscellaneous clippings, undated; 0031142040610100 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Published short stories by Harold Waters and Aubrey Wisberg: "High Jinks on the High Seas," "The Ready Box," "Puss Ahoy!", undated; 0031142040610100 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Passover Haggadah deluxe edition, undated; 0031142040610100 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Neanderthal Man, distribution statement from MGM/UA Entertainment Company, undated; 0031142040610100 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Aubrey Wisberg Credits, undated; 0031142040610100 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Florida Motion picture and Television Regulation Directory, undated; 0031142040610100 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Miscellaneous photographs, undated; 0031142040610100 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Unity Scroll from the International Unity Awards Committee for The Burning Cross, Awarded 1948 (Oversize 11, Folder 1)
  - Gondola, lyrics by Aubrey Wisberg, music by Albert Glasser, undated (Oversize 11, Folder 2)
  - Please Do Not Disturb!! lyrics by Aubrey Wisberg, music by Albert Glasser, undated (Oversize 11, Folder 3)
  - Silhouette, lyrics by Aubrey Wisberg, music by Albert Glasser, undated (Oversize 11, Folder 4)
  - LP 78 recordings Please Do Not Disturb, Cravat, date 8/16/53 crossed out. Soundcraft "Audition" outside-in, Gondola, lyrics by Aubrey Wisberg, music by Albert Glasser, sung by Noel Cravat, date 8/20/53 crossed out. Audiodisc recording blank, undated (Oversize 11, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous scrapbook pages, undated (Oversize 11, Folder 6)
  - Second Floor Front performance poster. Rye Center for the Performing Arts, Rye New York University. Presented by Central 111 Productions Fenimore Players, directed by George Ludgate, undated (Oversize 11, Folder 7)